(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-28T00:52:00.395942",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
進め↑ BAKATARATION
Advance! BAKATARATION!
新しい時代進んでく私たち
Moving forward into a new era, us
みんなで進もー！レッツゴー！
Let's all advance! Let's go!
朝まで騒ごう夜更かしは悪くないよね？
Let's party until morning, staying up late isn't bad, right?
悪くないよね？
Isn't bad, right?
世界揺らげるくらい強い絆の中で
Within bonds strong enough to shake the world,
ハイになってGo！
Get hyped and go!
尻尾振ってGo！
Wag your tail and go!
釣り合わん、バカタレーション！
Mismatched, BAKATARATION!
楽しんじゃえ Delight！
Have fun, Delight!
聞かせてよねサンライト！今夜もそうノリをまけテンションで
Let us hear it, sunlight! Tonight too, let loose with high tension,
私たちがナンバーワン！いつだってオンリーワン！
We are number one! Always the only one!
これまでもそうここからもずっと
Up until now, and from here on too, always,
ワクワクは続いてくよ！
The excitement will keep going!
初めての扉さぁ、ドンドン開けていこう
Let's open our very first door wide open!
怖がらずに行こー！
Let's go without fear!
ついついやさぐれでも一人じゃない…よね？
Even if we get cynical, we're not alone... right?
一人じゃない…よね？
We're not alone... right?
迷ってもいいよだって寄り道もイベントだし
It's okay to get lost, because detours are events too!
前のめりGo！
Lean forward and go!
助走つけGo！
Take a run-up and go!
まだまだ、バカタレーション！
Still more, BAKATARATION!
駆け抜けてこー！はしゃぎながらAll days！
Let's run through! Having fun all days!
ノリノリでノリでまけ太鼓ら！
Grooving along, beating the drums!
地球は広いけどまるっと一周
The earth is wide, but going all the way around,
シアワセで侵略できそう、きっと！
We can conquer it with happiness, surely!
ドタバタは続いてくよ！
The hustle and bustle will keep going!
今日のバカタレ2周年記念ライブだー！
Today is Bakatare's 2nd anniversary live!
ここでちょっと意気込みひとりずつ言ってみよう！
Let's each share our enthusiasm here one by one!
じゃあまずは私から！はーい！
First up is me! Yay!
バカタレらしいライブをするのでみんなついてきてね！
We're gonna put on a typical Bakatare live, so everyone follow along!
次は、次もたけちゃん、よろしくね！
Next, next is Take-chan, please!
尻尾もたくさん盛り上がるから、みんなもついてきてね！
The tail wags will hype things up a lot, so everyone follow along too!
そして最後はフブちゃん！
And last is Fubu-chan!
今日はみんなで楽しむぞ！よろしくね！
Today we'll all have fun together! Nice to meet you!
遊び足りない日はもう少し一緒に、もっともっと一緒に
On days when we haven't played enough, a little longer together, more and more together
みんなでときめこう無敵な友情未来へと振りかざして
Let's all flutter with excitement, wielding an invincible friendship toward the future!
さぁ、進め↑ BAKATARATION！
Now, advance! BAKATARATION!
楽しんじゃえ Delight！
Have fun, Delight!
聞かせてよねサンライト！今夜もそうノリをまけテンションで
Let us hear it, sunlight! Tonight too, let loose with high tension,
私たちがナンバーワン！いつだってオンリーワン！
We are number one! Always the only one!
これまでもそうここからもずっと
Up until now, and from here on too, always,
ワクワクは続いてくよ！
The excitement will keep going!
ゴー！レッツゴー！
Go! Let's go!
星獣戦隊ギンガマン
Seijuu Sentai Gingaman
走れ地球せましと駆け巡れギンガマン
Run, Gingaman, racing across the narrow earth!
走れ
Run!
たった一人でも君を守りたい
Even if I'm all alone, I want to protect you
いつも いつも いつも いつも
Always, always, always, always
側にいるから
I'll be by your side
どんなに辛くて どんなに苦しくても
No matter how painful or difficult it gets,
きっと きっと きっと きっと
Surely, surely, surely, surely
ゴールは近いから
The goal is near
星空に 輝けギンガ
Shine in the starry sky, Ginga
もう一度 君に会うために
To meet you once again
大地を掴む足音を聴け
Hearing the footsteps seizing the earth,
強く 激しく
Strong and intense
誰よりも温かく
Warmer than anyone else,
燃える太陽を引き上げるのさ
Raising the burning sun higher
ギンガ！
Ginga!
ガンガンギ・ギ・ギンガマン
Gangan Gi-Gi-Gingaman!
いつつの叫び どろろかせ
Startle the world with a sudden shout!
ガンガンギ・ギ・ギンガマン
Gangan Gi-Gi-Gingaman!
銀河を貫く 伝説の刃
Piercing through the darkness, the legendary blade!
星獣戦隊ギンガマン
Seijuu Sentai GINGAMAN!
走れ 星も光も追い越して
Run, leaving stars and light behind!
ギンガ！
Ginga!
闇を切り裂く虹になれ
Slice through the darkness, become a rainbow!
ギンガ！
Ginga!
ガンガンギ・ギ・ギンガマン
Gangan Gi-Gi-Gingaman!
明日を目指す瞳を残せ
Leave behind a twinkle as you aim for tomorrow!
強く 優しく 誰よりも熱く
Strong, gentle, and warmer than anyone else,
燃える太陽を信じてるのさ
Believing in the burning sun!
ギンガ！
Ginga!
ガンガンギ・ギ・ギンガマン
Gangan Gi-Gi-Gingaman!
いつつの願いを胸にひれえ
Embrace your five wishes to your chest!
ガンガンギ・ギ・ギンガマン
Gangan Gi-Gi-Gingaman!
銀河を貫く 伝説の刃
Piercing through the darkness, the legendary blade!
星獣戦隊ギンガマン
Seijuu Sentai GINGAMAN!
ガンガンギ・ギ・ギンガマン
Gangan Gi-Gi-Gingaman!
いつつの叫び どろろかせ
Startle the world with a sudden shout!
ガンガンギ・ギ・ギンガマン
Gangan Gi-Gi-Gingaman!
銀河を貫く 伝説の刃
Piercing through the darkness, the legendary blade!
星獣戦隊ギンガマン
Seijuu Sentai GINGAMAN!
それではですね、バカタラパーリー、イェーイ！
Well then, BakaTaran Party, yay!
バカタラパーリー、イェーイ！遅れちゃって失礼いたします。
BakaTaran Party started late, my apologies!
ちょっと馬に乗らせていただきまして！
We let you ride on the horses!
なんか走ってましたね、この子可愛い。
And you were running, how cute!
あれ、待って、あれ、最初の馬じゃ、羊？
Wait, was that a sheep?
いや、馬じゃないの。
No, it's not a horse!
馬か！
It's a horse!
羊じゃないよ。
It's not a sheep!
馬か！
It's a horse!
可愛い。
Cute!
ということでですね、1曲目はですね、
So, the first song was...
「進め！バカタラション」でし…あ、「ギンガマン」でした！
"Gingaman" was performed! Yay!
イェーイ！
Yay!
お礼のダンスをちらっと間違えた人がいたような気がするんですが。
Wait, did someone get the dance wrong?
はい！
Yes!
はい、間違えました。
Yes, I made a mistake!
最後ね、あの…
Finally, well...
まー！
Yay!
ねぇ、あのオープニングとかに馬が出てたのでね、ちょっと馬を用意していただきました！
Since horses appeared in the opening and all, we had some horses prepared for us!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
乗れて嬉しいね。
I'm so glad we could ride them.
乗れてよかったね。
I'm so glad we got to ride.
降りることもできるけど、一切降りなかったね二人とも。
We could get off, but neither of you got off at all.
可愛いから乗って、ずっと乗ったままやんけと思って。
Because they're cute, I figured we'd just stay riding them the whole time.
で、このMCずっとこのままですか？
So, is this MC going to stay like this the whole time?
降りる？降りるもまだ始まったばっかりでね、まだ他にも何回もね、やろうよねMCね。
We can get off, but the stream just started, so there'll be plenty more times we'll do MCs, right?
確かに。おしゃべりしててと思うから、まあ最初は、まあね、高いから、七夕だし、この辺にね、
True. We'll be chatting away, so for starters, well, you know, since it's Tanabata...
テロップで私たちの名前のセットっておいてください。
Please put up text overlays of our names around here.
あそこにね、誰々です誰々ですみたいな。そうそうそうそう。お願いします！お願いします！
Right over there, like "This is so-and-so." Yes, yes. Please! Please!
この後もね、確かにMCもありますし、曲もね、もういっぱい歌っていこうと思いますので、今日はよろしくお願いいたします！
After this, of course there'll be MCs and songs too, so we're looking forward to today!
いっぱい盛り上がっていこうぜ！頭、ことこと歩いてるけど大丈夫か？帰りたくなった？もしかして。
Let's get super hyped up! Wait, your head is bobbing along, are you okay? Do you want to go home?
早く帰りたい。早く帰ろうとしてる？肩が！肩がぶつかってる。
I want to go home quickly. Are you trying to go home? Your shoulders are bumping!
じゃあ次の曲の準備をしにじゃあ行きますか？
Shall we go get ready for the next song then?
はい！はい！じゃあ次の曲もお楽しみに！ばいばーい！あー、馬なのにー！
Yes! Then look forward to the next song! Bye-bye! Ah, but we're on horses!
そっちに降りちゃうんか。
You're getting off on that side.
( いくよー！)
(Here we go!)
まみむめモヤモヤなキミも are you ready？ 準備はいい？ (はーい！)
Even you, all fuzzy and gloomy, are you ready? Is everyone ready? (Yes!)
スキップ & クラップ で いち にー さん はい！
Skip and clap, one, two, three, go!
ポジティブ ☆ ダンスタイム
Positive ☆ Dance Time
夢色を奏でる夜空でさ shall we dance！？
Playing dream colors in the night sky, shall we dance!?
明日に笑われる くらい
Enough to make tomorrow laugh at us,
しかめ面お月様も一緒に shall we dance！？
Even the scowling moon together, shall we dance!?
最高のごきげんね 1 2 3 の リズム で
In the best mood possible, to a 1-2-3 rhythm,
1 2 3 魔法をかけて キミだけの ステップ だから
1, 2, 3, casting a magic spell, it's your very own step,
世界が ほら 輝く の
So the world, look, shines bright.
wake up！ wake up！ 遅れないでよ 魅惑のダンスタイム
Wake up! Wake up! Don't be late, enchanting dance time!
jumping！ jumping！ 恥ずかしがらずに
Jumping! Jumping! Without being shy,
fly！ high！ fly！ high！
Fly! High! Fly! High!
出し出したい 出し出したい パーピプペ ポジティブダンスタイム
I want to put it out, Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe Positive Dance Time!
変なことも レッタ レッタ レッタ キミと一緒に踊れば
Even weird things, letter by letter, if we dance together with you,
出し出したい 出し出したい 今はぎこちない リズム でも
I want to put it out, even with our clumsy rhythm right now,
青空にlet 's be ambitious！ きっと 輝く から
Let's be ambitious into the blue sky! It will surely shine.
まみむめノリノリなキミも are you ready？ 準備はいい？ (はーい！)
Even you, all pumped up, are you ready? Is everyone ready? (Yes!)
スキップ & クラップ で いち にー さん はい！
Skip and clap, one, two, three, go!
ポジティブ ☆ ダンスタイム
Positive ☆ Dance Time
雲色を奏でる夜空でさ shall we dance！？
Playing cloud colors in the night sky, shall we dance!?
昨夜を笑い飛ばす くらい
Enough to laugh off last night,
泣き虫なお星様も一緒に shall we dance！？
Even the crybaby stars together, shall we dance!?
笑顔ににしちゃうお 最高のごきげんね
Let's turn it into a smile, in the best mood possible,
1 2 3 の リズム で 1 2 3 魔法をかけて
To a 1-2-3 rhythm, casting a 1, 2, 3 magic spell,
キミだけの ステップ だから 世界が ほら 輝いた！
Your very own step, so the world, look, started shining!
wake up！ wake up！ 止まらないでよ 素敵なダンスタイム
Wake up! Wake up! Don't stop, wonderful dance time!
jumping！ jumping！ 無我夢中で ほら
Jumping! Jumping! Lost in the moment, look,
fly！ high！ fly！ high！ イェーイ！
Fly! High! Fly! High! Yay!
出し出したい 出し出したい パーピプペ ポジティブダンスタイム
I want to put it out, Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe Positive Dance Time!
前を向いて レッタ レッタ レッタ キミと一緒に奏でよう
Looking forward, letter by letter, let's play it together with you,
出し出したい 出し出したい 今はなれない メロディ でも
I want to put it out, even with an unfamiliar melody,
夢色にlet 's be ambitious！ きっと 届く から (準備はいい？)
Let's be ambitious into the dream colors! It will surely reach. (Are you ready?)
wake up！ wake up！ 遅れないでよ 超最高 のダンスタイム
Wake up! Wake up! Don't be late, super ultimate dance time!
jumping！ jumping！ 思いのまま ほら
Jumping! Jumping! Just as you feel, look,
fly！ high！ fly！ high！ high！ high！ high！ high！
Fly! High! Fly! High! High! High! High! High!
だから 素晴らしい の
That's why it's so wonderful.
dancing ☆ dancing ☆ time！
Dancing ☆ Dancing ☆ Time!
wake up！ wake up！ 遅れないでよ 超最高 のダンスタイム
Wake up! Wake up! Don't be late, super ultimate dance time!
jumping！ jumping！ 思いのまま ほら fly！ high！ fly！ high！ high！ high！ high！ high！
Jumping! Jumping! Just as you feel, look, fly! high! fly! high! high! high! high! high!
だから 素晴らしい の 出し出したい 出し出したい パーピプペ ポジティブ ダンスタイム
That's why it's so wonderful. I want to put it out, Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe Positive Dance Time!
涙拭いて レッタ レッタ レッタ キミと一緒に踊れば
Wipe away your tears, letter by letter, if we dance together with you,
出し出したい 出し出したい 今はまわりの キャンバス も
I want to put it out, even the canvas around us right now,
キミ色にlet 's be ambitious！ 描ける の (もう一回！)
Let's be ambitious in your color! We can paint it. (One more time!)
ポジティブ ☆ ダンスタイム！
Positive ☆ Dance Time!
出し出したい 出し出したい パーピプペ ポジティブダンスタイム
I want to put it out, Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe Positive Dance Time!
みんなでさっさ レッタ レッタ レッタ 楽しい楽しい 優勝 だね
Everyone, sass-ass, letter by letter, it's a fun, fun victory!
虹色の毎日 を ずっとずっと笑い疲れるくらい踊っていたい let 's be ambitious！ でも今日は おやすみ
I want to dance through rainbow-colored days until we're tired of laughing, let's be ambitious! But today, good night.
まみむめモヤモヤなキミも are you ready？ 準備はいい？ (はーい！ はいはい はーい！)
Even you, all fuzzy and gloomy, are you ready? Is everyone ready? (Yes! Yes yes, yes!)
行くよー！
Let's go!
まみむめモヤモヤなキミも
Even you, feeling hesitant and hazy,
Are you ready? 準備はいい？
Are you ready? Are you prepared?
（はーい！）
(Yeah!)
スキップ & クラップ で いち にー さん はい！
Skip & clap, one, two, three, go!
ポジティブ☆ダンスタイム
Positive Dance Time!
胸ぐらを掴まれて 強烈なパンチを
Grabbed by the collar, taking an intense punch,
喰らってよろけて 肩を並べずまったり
staggering back, crouching shoulder to shoulder.
予報通りの雨に お前にはにかんで
Smiling sheepishly at you in the expected rain,
「傷口が綺麗になる」なんて嘘をつく
telling a lie that "our wounds will look beautiful."
いつも口喧嘩さえ うまく出来ないくせして
Even though we can never argue properly,
呆れない冗談言うなよ
don't tell such absurd jokes.
あまりのつまらなさに 目に涙が浮かんで
So boring it brought tears to my eyes,
何度も青あざめいて涙を 流して流して
bruised and battered, shedding tears over and over,
不安定な心を肩に抱きあいながら
holding our unstable hearts on each other's shoulders
腐りきったバッドエンドに抗う
fighting against a thoroughly rotten bad ending.
なぜだろう 喜びよりも心地よい
Why does pain feel more comforting than joy,
痛みずっしりと響いて
resonating heavily inside?
濡れた服に舌うちしながら
Tsking at our wet clothes,
腫れ上がった顔見合って笑う
we look at our swollen faces and laugh.
土砂降りの夜に誓ったリベンジ
Vowing revenge on a torrential rainy night.
胸ぐらを掴み返して 反撃のパンチを
Grabbing back by the collar, throwing a counter punch
繰り出すくらいじゃなきゃ お前の隣には立てないから
unless I do that, I can't stand by your side.
相手が誰であれ怯えない
I won't be scared no matter who the opponent is,
何度もされても諦めない
won't give up even if knocked down repeatedly.
忘れるな忘れるなと言い聞かせ続けたのに
Even though I kept telling myself not to forget,
ああ 傘はいらないから言葉をひとつくれないか
Ah, I don't need an umbrella, won't you give me a word?
ぬるい優しさではなく 弱音に侵された胸の奥を
Not tepid kindness, but words that tear open the depths of my heart
えぐるような言葉を
invaded by weakness...
何度も青あざめいて涙を 流して流して
bruised and battered, shedding tears over and over,
不安定な心を肩に抱きあいながら
holding our unstable hearts on each other's shoulders
腐りきったバッドエンドに抗う
fighting against a thoroughly rotten bad ending.
なぜだろう 喜びよりも心地よい
Why does pain feel more comforting than joy
痛みずっしりと響いて
resonating heavily inside?
濡れた服に舌うちしながら
Tsking at our wet clothes,
腫れ上がった顔見合って笑う
we look at our swollen faces and laugh.
囚われた日々に 問いかけるように
To the days trapped, like asking a question
光った瞳の中で 誓ったリベンジ
within those glowing eyes, we vowed revenge.
ああ 傘はいらないから言葉をひとつくれないか
Ah, I don't need an umbrella, won't you give me a word?
ぬるい優しさではなく
Not tepid kindness,
弱音に侵された胸の奥をえぐるような言葉を
words that tear open the depths of my heart invaded by weakness...
何度も青あざめいて涙を 流して流して
bruised and battered, shedding tears over and over,
不安定な心を肩に抱きあいながら
holding our unstable hearts on each other's shoulders
腐りきったバッドエンドに抗う
fighting against a thoroughly rotten bad ending.
なぜだろう 喜びよりも心地よい
Why does pain feel more comforting than joy
痛みずっしりと響いて
resonating heavily inside?
濡れた服に舌うちしながら
Tsking at our wet clothes,
腫れ上がった顔見合って笑う
we look at our swollen faces and laugh.
土砂降りの夜に誓ったリベンジ
Vowing revenge on a torrential rainy night.
囚われた日々に 問いかけるように
To the days trapped, like asking a question
光った瞳の中で 誓ったリベンジ
within those glowing eyes, we vowed revenge.
ふー… はぁ… ということ、あ、漫才組みたいになってますけどどうも！
Phew... Ha... So, uh, it's like a manzai duo now, hello!
どうして！？ どうして！？
Why?! Why?!
なんで戦ってるの？わからないけどめちゃくちゃしちゃった。
Why are we fighting? I don't know, but we totally messed up.
そうなんだ。なんかちょっと気になっちゃったんだ。
Is that so? I just got a bit curious.
そうすだけいけない気がしてさ、気持ちよく歌ってたのにさ！
I felt like I had to do it, even though I was singing so comfortably!
やっちゃったよ。
We really did it.
殴り合いとする拳で、ポジティブを高めてた、イェーイ！イェーイ！
Fist-fighting to raise our positivity, yay! Yay!
バカタレってそういう感じなんだ。
So that's what 'Bakatare' is like.
そうだよ！いまさら？ イェーイ！ イェーイ！ イェーイ！
That's right! Only realizing this now? Yay! Yay! Yay!
ということでね、「ポジティブ☆ダンスタイム」と「Cry Baby」お届けできました！ありがとうございましたー！
So, we delivered 'Positive Dance Time' and 'Cry Baby'! Thank you very much!
あーまずね、ポジティブダンスタイムなんですけども
Ah, first off, it's Positive Dance Time, but...
もうグダグダだったよね
It was a total mess, wasn't it?
グダグダだったよね
A total mess!
集中しすぎて合わせようと思ってたところが全然ダンス合わなくて
We were so focused on trying to sync up that our dances didn't match at all.
あとね、フブちゃんしょっぱなも
Also, Fubuki-chan, right at the start...
なんだったの？
What was that?
踊る曲じゃないわ
It's not a song you dance to!
ちょっとね、思ってた、思ってたけども、まあポジティブダンスタイムだけと
I mean, I thought so, I thought so, but I said "just Positive Dance Time"
か、他も合わせようって言ったけど、ダメでしたー
and that we'd match the rest too, but it didn't work out!
なんか、みんなを切り抜く時はね、できてるこ切抜いてもらったよ
You know, when people make clips, make sure they clip the parts where we actually did it right.
そうだね、そうだね！できてるとこね！
That's right, that's right! The parts where we succeeded!
ポジティブダンスタイム！ 1回だけ合ってるはず！
Positive Dance Time! It should be right at least once!
1回だけできてたから！ 1回だけ合ってるのね！ お願いします！ お願いします！
We did it right once! It matched just once! Please! Please!
そして乙女の、はい！出だしなんだこれ、で、ダンスかっ！今日最初でしょ？
And then a maiden's... yes! What kind of intro is that, dancing?! Is this our first time today?
今日最初だった！そうしょっぱなじゃないでしょ？そう、だからリベンジするんでしょ、でも
It was our first time today! So it wasn't the very start, right? Yeah, that's why we're getting our revenge, but...
今日最初だけどリベンジするんだよ二人でな！
It's our first time today, but we're getting our revenge together, right?!
そうそう、そうだね！
Yeah, yeah, that's right!
二人にリベンジを！
Revenge for the two of us!
夜がどうした！どうした！あそこもかっこよかったよ！よかったねー！
Night is what! What! That part looked cool too! It was great!
すごい気持ちよく歌ってたのにね、二人後ろで何やってたのかな？
We were singing so comfortably, but what were the two of you doing in the back?
いやなんか、あれはね、ポーズがね、ポーズが、あ、みんな行っちゃった？
Well, you know, that was... the poses, ah, did everyone go?
闘争心、闘争心
Fighting spirit, fighting spirit.
体は闘争を求める、このあとの闘争の曲いっぱいあるからね
The body craves conflict, there are lots of conflict songs after this.
ああ確かに、そのあともちょっとの、あの、熱い、ね、あっちっちの
Ah, true, after that too, some hot, you know, piping hot...
あっちっちなのやってた！
You were doing the piping hot thing!
まだまだ二人にはね、体力続く限り頑張ってもらいましょう！
Let's have the two of them keep doing their best as long as they have stamina!
本当に、結構今の限界だったよ、フブちゃん大丈夫？
Seriously, that was pretty much my limit right now. Fubuki-chan, are you okay?
確かにちょっとね、まだあるよ
True, there's still more, you know.
終わった後に二人で、はあーーっ！
After it ended, the two of us went, "Haahhh!"
え、待って、大丈夫？
Wait, are you okay?
大丈夫、全然大丈夫だよ！さっき殴ったのが負傷になってない？大丈夫？
I'm fine, totally fine! Didn't the punch from earlier cause an injury? Are you okay?
うん、いまんとこ大丈夫！あ、ここから来るかもしれないよ
Yeah, it's fine for now! Ah, it might come from here onwards.
というか、次の曲は？あれ？二人でデュエット？
Or rather, the next song? Huh? A duet by the two of you?
かっこよくやっちゃう！めちゃめちゃ泥臭くない？
Doing it cool! Isn't it super muddy/rough?
それはちょっと、だから、泥臭くない？ちょっととりあえず急ごう、あ、泥臭い、殴り合いみたいな感じいく？
That's a bit, so, isn't it muddy? Let's hurry for now, ah, muddy, like a fistfight, shall we go with that?
ちょっと、ぶつかっちゃう
Wait, we'll bump into each other!
本当に怖いですね、ちょっと、ちょっと、お手柔らかにしときましょうかねっていうことで
It's really scary, let's take it easy, shall we?
このあとは二人のデュエットでーーす！はーい！
So after this, it's a duet by the two of them! Yay!
かっこよく決めるぜ！おっけー！
We'll nail it coolly! Okay!
打ち疲れたこの鼓動は無力で儚いもの
This exhausted heartbeat is powerless and fleeting.
痛みは空よりも麗かに
Pain is more radiant than the sky.
アイアイエー オマアイオー
Ay-ay-eh, oh-my-oh
屋上に空があった 風も、熱も、夢も、明日も
There was a sky on the rooftop—wind, heat, dreams, tomorrow too.
空気中に彷徨った 理想、怒り、視線、刹那
Wandering in the air—ideals, anger, gazes, a fleeting moment.
渦を巻くような 暗く深い場所 ジリジリ音をたてて絡め取れ
A dark, deep place like a swirling vortex, making a crackling sound as it entangles you.
数えきれ程の瞳が全部笑ったら
When countless eyes all burst into laughter,
後ろの正面その目は誰？
whose eyes are those right behind us?
アイアイエー オマアイオー…
Ay-ay-eh, oh-my-oh...
までで闇に描かれた 叶わない夢模様
Like a dream pattern drawn in darkness that will never come true,
髪を振り乱すような 気配がざわめく
a presence that makes your hair stand on end stirs up.
やがてそこに訪れた 両手に余る悲しみ
Before long, a grief too great to hold in both hands visited there,
叫びは高らかに 慈しむほど 痛みは空よりも麗かに
and the cry rings high—the more you cherish it, the more radiant the pain is than the sky.
痛みは空よりも麗かに 追想のディスペア
Pain is more radiant than the sky—Despair of Reminiscence.
アイアイエー オマアイオー
Ay-ay-eh, oh-my-oh
凍り付いて誰が笑う 染まる嘆く疼く叫ぶ
Who is laughing while frozen? Dyed, mourning, throbbing, screaming.
瞳いって目に 見えない 意識 言葉 不安 未来
Eyes closed, unseen, consciousness, words, anxiety, future.
咽る乾き巻くの狂気は 口元が不自然に引きつったまま
Choking, drying, swirling madness with mouths unnaturally twitching.
おいででおいでされたら 最後 さようならも言えず
If you are beckoned and welcomed, in the end you won't even be able to say goodbye.
目が合えば早い呼吸になる ああいやいや
If our eyes meet, our breathing quickens—ah, no, no, no.
アイアイエー オマアイオー
Ay-ay-eh, oh-my-oh
打ち疲れた この体を 無力で儚いもの
My exhausted body, so powerless and fleeting,
爪で切りむしるような わずかな残像
a faint afterimage like being clawed apart.
そして海に落ち込んだ 箱詰めの記憶と
And packed memories that fell into the sea,
壊滅線を描く 赤い奇跡は
the red miracle drawing a line of devastation.
最上の祭壇に彩られ
Adorned on the supreme altar,
追憶のディスペア
the despair of reminiscence.
まるで闇に描かれた 叶わない夢模様
Like a hopeless dream drawn in darkness,
髪を振り乱すような 気配がざわめく
a rustling presence that tosses hair about.
やがて其処に訪れた 両手に余る悲しみ
Sorrow overflowing both hands arriving there,
叫びは誰かに慈しむほど
cries as if pitying someone so much,
痛みは空よりも愚かに
pain more foolish than the sky.
追憶のディスペア
The despair of reminiscence.
もしも生まれ変わっても また私に生まれたい
Even if I'm reborn, I want to be born anew,
この体とこの色で 生き抜いてきたんだから
because I've lived through it with this body.
いつか太陽が消えてなくなる前に
Before the sun disappears and vanishes,
もっとあなたを好きなこと 伝えなくちゃ
I must tell you how much I love you.
欲張りな私 好きになったなら
If a greedy me has come to love you,
完璧にあなたを 捕まえてみたい
I want to capture you completely.
あなたの細胞 少しも残さず盗まなくちゃ
I've got to steal every last cell of yours,
満足しないのよ うまくいかない程やりがいがあるわ！
or I won't be satisfied!
恋も夢も食べまくって 叶えられるよきっと
Eating my fill of love and dreams,
もしも生まれ変わっても また私に生まれたい
Even if I'm reborn, I want to be born anew,
この体とこの色で 生き抜いてきたんだから
because I've lived through it with this body.
いつか太陽が消えてなくなる前に
Before the sun disappears and vanishes,
もっとあなたを好きなこと 伝えなくちゃ
I must tell you how much I love you.
許されるためのずるい悪戯も
Even sly mischief meant to be forgiven,
やり尽くしてたどり着いた性格も
and this personality forged at the limit,
黄色い映画に出てるみたいだと笑うけど
You laugh, saying it's like a yellow movie,
うらやましがってる
but you're actually envious.
リアルはいつも嘘の中にある
Reality is always hidden within lies,
誰も本当のことなんて教えてくれないから
because no one tells you the truth.
あなた泣かせる力があれば 笑う力もあると信じているのよ
If I can make you cry, I can make you smile.
もしも生まれ変わっても また私に生まれたい
Even if I were reborn, I'd want to be born as myself again,
この体と この色で 生きてきたんだから
because I've lived on with this body and this color.
いつか太陽が消えてなくなる前に もっとあなたを好きなこと伝えなくちゃ
Before the sun eventually fades away, I have to tell you how much I love you.
強欲な私 好きになったなら 完璧をつかまえてみたい
If you've grown to like greedy ol' me, I want to try grabbing hold of perfection.
あなたの細胞 少しも残さず盗めなくちゃ 満足しないのよ
I've gotta steal every single cell of yours without leaving any behind, or I won't be satisfied!
みんな 欲しがる お金で 黄色い 小犬を 買った
Everyone bought a yellow puppy with the money they desire.
みんな 欲しがる 幸せ 強く 強く 抱きしめたい
Everyone wants happiness; I want to hold it close, tightly, tightly.
もしも 生まれ変わっても また 私に 生まれたい
Even if I were reborn, I'd want to be born as myself again,
この 体と この 色で 生きてきたんだから
because I've lived on with this body and this color.
すべては 私が 私で いる ために
Everything is so that I can remain myself,
すべては すべては 「happy」の ために
and everything, everything is for "happiness."
太陽 が 消えて なくなる 前に
Before the sun eventually fades away,
もっと あなたを 好きな こと 伝えなくちゃ
I have to tell you how much I love you.
はい、ということで！
Yes, and so!
いやあ、後ろのね、がっつり進んだのが
Man, that intense progression in the back—
もう
Already...
はあ、ということでですね。
Right, so anyways,
はあ、ぎりぎり いただきましたー！
Whew, we barely made it through!
これきつかったわ。
That was tough.
大丈夫ですか、お二人とも。
Are you two okay?
硬い手は
Your stiff hands—
痙攣になりそうだわ。
are about to cramp up!
すごい引けてたよ、めっちゃ動いてて。
You were pulling away so much, moving like crazy!
ということでじゃ一旦、楽器には消えていただきましょうかね。
So, let's have the instruments disappear for a moment, shall we?
はい、おーん、消えろー！
Yep, poof, disappear!
はい、なくなりましたー。
There they go, gone.
ということでですね、演奏のディスペア。
So, the performance despair...
まず最初に、聞いていただきましたけども、お二人めちゃめちゃかっこよかったと。
First off, we played that for you, and you two were super cool.
いやあ、すごいよかったよ。
Man, it was really great.
え、誰が選曲したんだい、これ？
Huh, who chose this song anyway?
これは…、え、でもなんか私かな？
This is... uh, but I guess it was me?
私かな？
Was it me?
そうなんだ。
Is that so?
私が出したら、わためも知ってたんだね。
When I put it out, Watame knew it too.
そう、知ってて、お気に入りの曲。
Yeah, I knew it, it's one of my favorite songs.
そう、だからね、意外だったの、二人で歌えて嬉しかった。
Yeah, so it was surprising, I was happy we could sing it together.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
こちらこそよ。
Same here.
なかなかね、二人で歌うことあんまり、意外と確か に。
We don't usually sing together much, surprisingly, that's true.
ないね。やろうよ、もっと。
We don't. Let's do it more!
ね、もっとやろうよ。
Yeah, let's do it more.
もっと歌ってくださいよ。ね、ねごしましょ う。
Please sing more. Hey, let's negotiate.
そしたらふぶちゃんは、はい、私はですね、YELLOW YELLOW HAPPYという曲を歌っていただきました。
And then Fubuki-chan—yes, I had us sing the song "YELLOW YELLOW HAPPY."
知ってる人は知っている曲でございます。
It's a song that those in the know definitely know.
いやあ、でも二人もね、ちょっと。
Man, but you two also, you know...
とあるポジションとしてね、今回いて、いて。
You were in a certain position this time, and...
盛り上げてね、かき鳴らしていただきましたけども。
you hyped things up and strummed along for us.
いや、ちょうどこう、言わせて、一緒に。
Man, we just made them say it together.
札がすごいのおよ、後ろの。
Man, the cards in the back were intense!
そうね、笑わないように必死だった。
That's right, we were desperate not to laugh.
こんななってて、そうそう、めっちゃ。
Like this, yeah, totally.
いやだってそんな、なしでしょ。
I mean, come on, that's unfair.
恐ろしかったね、後ろの。
That back stuff was terrifying, wasn't it?
でも可愛かったね。
But it was cute!
いやでもよかったよかったいです、ありがとうございます。
Yeah, but it was great, thank you very much!
こちらこそ、こちらこそですよ。
Same here, absolutely same here.
でもなんか途中犬だと思ってなかった？
But didn't you think it was a dog midway?
あ、そう。
Oh, yeah.
あの、みんな欲しがるお金で黄色いわためを買ったの？
"Everyone bought a yellow Watame with the money they desire"?
犬だったね。
It was a dog.
どんなってこと？どんなどんなってこと？
What does that mean? What kind of thing is that?
どんなってこと？
What does that mean?
終活か。
End-of-life planning?
そう、終活か。終活か。
Yeah, end-of-life planning. End-of-life planning.
インフンデンじゃねえよ。
That's not what it means!
ねえ、いやもう本当に。
Hey, man, seriously.
ねえ、いやもう本当に、楽しかったです。でもこれで終わり？
Hey, seriously, it was so fun. But is that it?
え？まだある？まだあるよ。
Huh? There's more? There's more!
次の曲、えっとは？
The next song, um, is?
おおと？私と？
Oh? With me?
エルフゅっかされてきます。エルフゅっかね。
Being forcefully retired as an elf. Elf retirement.
バイバイ！バイバイ！
Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
バイバーイ！またね！バイバーイ！
Bye-bye! See you later! Bye-bye!
めぐりめぐる 君をたどる 僕のさがす すべてになった
Wandering and wandering, tracing you, you became everything I was searching for.
はかな落ちる 心が知ってた
My transiently falling heart knew it all along.
愛してる
I love you.
この空の下で二人
Beneath this sky, the two of us
ゆらりゆらり また風に吹かれ
Swaying, swaying, blown by the wind once more,
身を寄せ合ってゆく
drawing close to one another.
大きな時の流れの中で
Amidst the grand flow of time,
ボクは何を手にしたんだろう
what is it that I've obtained?
手荷物に集め 咲かせたものを
Things I gathered in my luggage and made bloom,
すぐに 枯らせてしまう
I let wither away in an instant.
黒い風に流され どこかで消える
Carried away by a dark wind, vanishing somewhere,
あるがままで生きようとする
trying to live just as I am,
あまり それさえも見えない
to the point where even that becomes invisible.
巡り巡る キミを辿る
Going round and round, tracing you,
ボクの探す すべてになった
you became everything I was searching for.
剥がれ落ちる 心がしてた
My heart had been peeling away,
愛してる
I love you.
この空の下で二人
Beneath this sky, the two of us
ゆらりゆらり また風に吹かれ
Swaying, swaying, blown by the wind once more,
身を寄せ合ってゆく
drawing close to one another.
ひとりきりの 愛情はキミに届くかな
Will my solo affection reach you, I wonder?
罪さまよった
Wandering in sin,
分かり合えるはずのキミが遠くて
you, who I should be able to understand, are so far away.
強くうねる吹雪のようなこのいら立ちだけ投げた
I just threw out this frustration like a fiercely howling blizzard.
巡り巡る キミを辿る
Going round and round, tracing you,
ボクに足りないもの
what was lacking in me
剥がれ落ちる 心にしみて 痛み出した 締め付ける
soaked into my peeling heart, began to ache and tighten.
空の色と心をつなぐ キミの涙だけのりに焼き付く
Connecting the sky's color and my heart, only your tears are burned into my memory.
キミに触れ キミを抱き ぬくもりや呼吸を感じ
Touching you, holding you, feeling your warmth and breath,
二人の愛 答え知りにしたと信じてた
I believed I had come to know the answer to our love.
だけどいま キミの中 苦しみや悲しみに触れてしまった
But now, I've touched upon the pain and sorrow inside you,
気付いてしまった ボクはそれを恐れてたんだ
and realized I had been afraid of it.
巡り巡る キミを辿る
Going round and round, tracing you,
ボクがすべて抱いてあげる
I will embrace all of it for you.
そしてここに二人で出逢え
And meeting here together,
さあ 咲かせよう 名も知らぬ花でもいい 枯れぬように優しく包んで ずっと咲かせると
let's make it bloom—even if it's an unknown flower, gently wrap it so it won't wither, and let it bloom forever.
キミがいる こころ それだけで 絡みつく
You are in my heart, and with just that, clinging...
闇も光へと 約束の星を抱きしめて
Turning even darkness into light, embracing the promised star,
飛び立つ今
taking flight right now
輝きへと
toward the radiance!
あの日の空が残した 笑顔のスケッチ
The sketch of a smile left behind by that day's sky,
胸の奥で溢れたんだ
overflowed deep within my chest.
こんな温かい涙
Such warm tears
初めてだよ
are a first for me.
勇気に変えて 歩いてこう
I'll turn them into courage and keep walking on.
時の風に包まれ
Wrapped in the wind of time,
切なさ舞うさようなら
farewell to the bittersweet dance.
いつかまた出会えるよね
Hoping we can meet again someday,
遠き空に約束
I make a promise to the distant sky.
君がいる
Knowing you are there
心それだけでも
is enough for my heart...
絡みつく 闇も光へと
even clinging darkness turns into light,
もう二度と 迷わないように
and I'll never get lost ever again.
たとえ雨が 降り続いてもう
Even if the rain continues to fall,
見つめていい あの雲の行方
I can keep gazing at where those clouds are heading.
追いかけて その先へ行くこう
Chasing after them, heading further ahead,
約束の 星を抱きしめて 飛び立つ今 輝きへと
embracing the promised star, taking flight right now toward the radiance!
新しい靴が痛くって
My new shoes hurt,
立ち止まって しまうこともあるけどね
and sometimes I stop in my tracks, but...
気まぐれ雲に差しくこむ
Piercing through the whimsical clouds,
夢の粒を そっと集めて 描いてこう
I'll softly gather seeds of dreams and sketch them out.
いつも 強がることで 強くなろうとした
Always trying to stay strong by acting tough,
割り切れない 心があるから 明日が生まれてくんだね
because I have a heart that can't be split, tomorrow is born.
君がいる 遠く離れても こんなにも側に歩き持ち
Even if you're far away, feeling you so close beside me as I walk...
もう一度 出会うその日まで 取っておきの 自分見つけよう
until the day we meet again, I'll find my own special treasure.
忘れない 大切に触れた かけがえのない 永遠の一秒
Never forgetting the eternal second when I touched something precious—
約束の 星に導かれ 続く道を 歩いて行く
guided by the promised star, I'll walk along the path that continues.
君がいる 遠く離れても こんなにも側に歩き持ち
Even if you're far away, feeling you so close beside me as I walk...
もう一度 出会うその日まで 取っておきの 自分見つけよう
until the day we meet again, I'll find my own special treasure.
忘れない 大切に触れた かけがえのない 永遠の一秒
Never forgetting the eternal second when I touched something precious—
約束の 星に導かれ 続く道を 歩いて行く
guided by the promised star, I'll walk along the path that continues.
かけがえのない 永遠の一秒 約束の 星に導かれ
The irreplaceable, eternal second, guided by the promised star,
続く道を 歩いてゆけ
walking along the path that continues...
君がいる 遠く離れても こんなにも側に歩き持ち
Even if you're far away, feeling you so close beside me as I walk...
君がいる
You are here...
あー！
Ah!
君がこっち来た！
You came over here!
私がいこっち来た！
I came over here!
僕がいる！
I'm here!
という ことで、君たちがいるよ。
That is to say, you guys are here.
おっと、私たちがいるよ。
Oh, we are here.
私たちがいるよー！
We are here!
そして私がいるー！
And I am here!
みんなもいるー！
Everyone is here too!
それがバカタレ！バカタレ！バカタレ！
That's Bakatare! Bakatare! Bakatare!
ポポポポココココー！バカタレ！
Popopopokokokoo! Bakatare!
という ことで、ね、2曲聞いていただきましたー！まずは白上とあめなの？
So, um, you listened to two songs! First, Shirakami and Watame's?
ローーーール！
Roooool!
なんかかね、そう、ローの歌うの実は？
You know, singing Roll, actually?
そう、初めてなんだよね！そうなんだよー。いやいや、初めてをいただきましたー！
Yeah, it's our first time! That's right. Hehe, thank you for the first time!
なんかこうてかったね、君たちね。
You guys looked kind of shiny.
あ、ちょっとね、いい感じに、ちょっと、のけもの？違うの！え、はい、入りなよ！
Ah, a little, nicely, kind of, outcast? No! Eh, yeah, get in!
あ、悪かったー！そんなー！
Ah, my bad! No way!
なんて言うよ。
What are you saying.
いや、ということでね、そのロールのね、選曲させていただきましたー！
Yeah, so, we chose to sing Roll!
すっごいよかったー！
It was so good!
ありがとー！うれしかったよ！
Thank you! I'm so glad!
いや何も特にしようかすっごい悩んだんだよね。ね、私元々からロール歌いたいなと思ってて
Yeah, I really struggled with what to choose. You know, I originally wanted to sing Roll
最初になんかメロメロのドラマティックいっとくかと思ったんだけど、それも可愛いよね。
At first I thought about doing a dreamy dramatic song, that's also cute.
でもね、なんかそののんびりした曲も欲しいなと思って、ロールにしました。
But I also wanted a laid-back song, so I chose Roll.
ナイス選曲！白上が一番好きな曲です、ロールは。
Nice song choice! Roll is the song Fubuki likes the most.
あ、そうなの？そうなんだよ、一番好きな曲をちょっとね、歌わせてもらいましたー！
Oh, is that so? Yeah, I got to sing my favorite song!
すごいよかった！ありがとー！またいつでも聞きたいな。
It was amazing! Thank you! I want to listen to it anytime again.
あ、三人で歌う？やろうやろう！
Ah, sing together as three? Let's do it!
かっけきよかっ そんな曲じゃないよ！やろう！ん、おめーら！
Such a cool song - no it's not! Let's do it! Hey, you guys!
ポルの3人になってしまう！二人削って。
It becomes three Pors! Two cut.
ジョバイロもいこう！ジョバイロいっとく？
Let's do Jobairo too! Shall we do Jobairo?
昔のポルのジョバイロ、ジョバイロ！ヒットオーバーノン！
The old Por's Jobairo, Jobairo! Hit over non!
ポルのシマダやる？ポルのサナイダやる？
Shall we do Por's Shimada? Por's Sanaida?
やろう！また何がいい？ポルの曲。
Let's do it! What else is good? Por's songs.
えー、何がいいかん、選べないんだよ！選べない！
Eh, which one is good, I can't choose! I can't choose!
アポロ！アポロ！アポロいっとく？
Apollo! Apollo! Shall we go with Apollo?
ポ、ポクラ
Po, Pokura
そんな低くない！なんてポクラ！アポロ引かれてる！
Not that low! What Pokura! Apollo is being pulled!
ちょっと、でもみんなでやろうよ。
Wait, but let's all do it together.
やりたいです、アポロのシマりもね！やりたいですな！
I want to do it, Apollo's conclusion too! I want to do it!
そしてそして、フリオの曲がこれはなんの曲なんだい？
And then, what song is Furio's song?
これわ、ガッシュの挿入歌ですね！ガッシュの挿入歌！約束の欲しい！
This is Gash's insert song! Gash's insert song! Promised Star!
ねえ、ねえ、だったよ！
Hey, hey, it was!
そう、めっちゃよかったよ！
Yeah, it was super good!
出だし以外はきれいだった！
Except for the start, it was pretty!
なんんでこれやっちゃったかな！
Why did I do this!
な、なんか、バタテのこんな感じの始まったから、やったほうがいいのかなと。
So, somehow, Bakatare started with this kind of vibe, so I thought I should do it.
いやいや、そしたら私もいろいろあぴてこうやってきちゃったよ！確かに！ねえ、これ早くない？
No no, then I also came up with various appeals! True! Hey, isn't this fast?
ツッ、ツッ、ツッ、パン！
Tsu, tsu, tsu, pan!
君がいる！だから、かっこよかったよ！かっこよかった！キレキレだったね！
You're here! That's why it was cool! It was cool! It was sharp!
そう、すごくよかったよもう。痺れたよね！
Yeah, it was really good. It gave me chills!
はーい。ま、ということで、じゃあ次の曲もありますので、そろそろ準備しましょうか！
Okay. Well, with that, we have another song next, so let's prepare soon!
はーい！
Okay!
はい！では、準備行くぞ！はけるぞ！
Yes! Well, let's go prepare! Let's clear the stage!
え、どっち？こっちこっち！どっちどっち？
Eh, which way? This way this way! Which way which way?
あ、どっちでもいいよ！どっちでもいいんかい！
Ah, either is fine! Whichever is fine!
カッコつけてるつもりで得意になって
Acting cool and getting full of myself,
大事なことは全部置き去りにしちゃって
Leaving all the important things behind.
自分自身で苦しんでいるシュウジンの
Torturing myself as a prisoner of my own making,
そんな僕にサヨナラさ Transformation!
Say goodbye to that self, Transformation!
暗闇が怖くてどうする
What will you do if you're scared of the darkness?
アイツが怖くてどうする 足踏みしてるだけじゃ進まない
What will you do if you're scared of them? Just marking time gets you nowhere.
男なら 誰かのために強くなれ 歯を食いしばって
If you're a man, grow strong for someone's sake, grit your teeth,
思いっきり守り抜け 転んでもいいよ また立ち上がればいい
And protect them with all your might. Fall down if you must, just get back up.
ただそれだけ できれば 英雄さ
Just that alone, if you can do it, you're a hero.
今日もなんだかやる気が起きないなんて
Even today, feeling somehow unmotivated,
甘え尽くしの自分が本当は嫌いで
I really hate this self that pampers and indulges itself.
とりあえずは外で深呼吸 更新
For now, take a deep breath outside and refresh.
カッコつけてるつもりで得意になって
Acting cool and getting full of yourself,
大事なものは全部置き去りにしちゃって Transformation!
leaving everything important behind. Transformation!
弱気になってどうする
What's the use of getting timid?
明日の君はどうする
What are you going to do tomorrow?
黙って下向いてちゃ聞こえない
If you just stay silent and look down, you won't hear a thing.
男なら 誰かのために強くなれ
If you're a man, be strong for someone's sake!
ぶつかり合って 精一杯やってみろ
Clash against it and give it your absolute all!
泣いてもいいよ また笑えればいい
It's okay to cry, as long as you can smile again.
ただそれだけ できれば 英雄さ
If you can just do that, you're a hero!
男なら 誰かのために強くなれ
If you're a man, be strong for someone's sake!
ぶつかり合って 精一杯やってみろ
Clash against it and give it your absolute all!
泣いてもいいよ また笑えればいい
It's okay to cry, as long as you can smile again.
ただそれだけ できれば 英雄さ
If you can just do that, you're a hero!
女もそうさ 見てただけじゃ始まらない
Same goes for you girls, watching won't get you started.
これが正しいって言える勇気があればいい
You just need the courage to say what's right.
ただそれだけ できれば 英雄さ
If you can just do that, you're a hero!
歯をくいしばって
Grit your teeth,
思いっきり守り抜け
and protect them with all your might!
転んでもいいよ また立ち上がればいい
It's okay to fall, just stand back up again.
ただそれだけ できれば 英雄さ
If you can just do that, you're a hero!
はーい！という事で……
Alright! So...
暴れた！暴れた！すごい！めっちゃ叫んだ！
We went wild! So wild! That was amazing, I screamed so much!
てかさ、みんなギターカッコいー！
Also, everyone's guitars look so cool!
なんかさ、何本ギター買ったんだよ！
Wait, how many guitars did you guys buy?!
1本ずつ買ったんだよ！いい感じにかっこいいって！
We each bought one! They look pretty cool, right!
いいじゃん！ガールズバンド感すごい！ガールズバンド感いいよ！
That's awesome! It gives off a huge girl band vibe, I love it!
俺がギターだ！いや俺もギターだ！じゃあベースのつもりだ！
I'm on guitar! No, I'm on guitar too! Then I guess I'm playing bass!
え、じゃあベース？ みんなベースなの！？
Wait, bass? Are you guys all playing bass?!
いやいや、ちょっと待って、じゃあギター消えろ！
No no, wait a second, then guitar disappear!
と言うことで、英雄でございました！
And that's how we performed 'Eiyuu'!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
いや楽しかったね！楽しかったね！
Man, that was so fun! So fun!
気持ちいい！気持ちいいだね！
It feels so good! Feels amazing!
いやーよかった！オーライがすごいみんな！ちゃんと歌えてよかったと思いました！
Man, that was great! Everyone's 'Alright!' was amazing! I'm glad we could sing it properly.
はい、はい、という事で、なんと！
Yes, yes, so, amazingly...
お？ これで終わりなの！？
Oh? Is this already the end?!
えー？ 1曲終わりなの？ まだまだあるよね？
Eh? Just one song? There's still more, right?
まだありますよね？ 次が最後の曲？
There's still more, right? Is the next one the last song?
えー！？ 1曲！？
Eh?! Just one song?!
ってことはさ、こういうのってさ、普段はさ、ここで
That means, normally in these situations, shouldn't there be...
告知とか感じじゃないの！？告知ないじゃん！
an announcement or something?! There's no announcement!
ないじゃん！告知ないじゃん！
There isn't! There's no announcement!
ないよ！ないよ！ないよ！
There isn't! There isn't!
まあまあ、あるでしょ、いろいろと！
Well, you know, there's all sorts of stuff!
ないよ！ないよ！いまはないけどさ、
There isn't! There isn't! Well, not right now, but...
まあ、今後ね、バカタレ、あるでしょ？いろいろと！
Well, going forward, the Bakatare Trio will have various things, right?
なんかあったっけ？ おいおいおい！俺俺俺！
Did something happen? Hey, hey, hey! Me, me, me!
え！？ 意外とさ、これ知らないけどさ！
Eh?! Surprisingly, I didn't know about this!
でもさ、耳あるよな？ 長い耳ついとるよな？
But hey, you have ears, right? You've got long ears, right?
ふわふわの耳付いてるよな？
You've got fluffy ears attached, right?
でも、あの、あれだね、これからもね、二人ともよろしくお願いします！
But, um, you know, let's keep working well together!
あ、よろしくお願いします！よろしくお願いします！
Ah, looking forward to it! Looking forward to it!
なんかタメ口になってる！
You're suddenly using casual speech!
え、ビジネスフレンドってこと！？いやバカタレはビジネスとして仲良くやっていくんだよ！
Eh, business friends?! No, Bakatare is going to get along strictly as business partners!
じゃあビジネスの心構えでね、これからは……
Then with that business mindset, from now on...
ちょっと！そんなこと言わないで！
Wait! Don't say things like that!
ちょっとみんなそういう時は無理って言うねん！やめて！やめて！
Wait, everyone says 'no way' at times like this! Stop it! Stop it!
とりあえず、やめろ！ビジネスって言うな！ビジネスって言うな！
Anyway, stop it! Don't call it business! Don't call it business!
じゃあまあ、あと1曲、あと1曲でございます！
Well then, we have one more song, just one more song left!
で、これでね、ちょっとMCパートが終わっちゃうんで、最後に一言ずつちょっと感想もらおうかな！
And since this wraps up the MC part, let's hear a brief final thought from each of us!
じゃあ、わためから！今回のバカタレライブどうでしたか？
Watame, how was this Bakatare Live?
え、何も考えてなかった！何も考えずにやってたか！
Uh, I didn't think about anything! I was just doing it without thinking!
でもやっぱ、音楽っていいよね！いいよね！
But music is really great, isn't it! It really is!
楽しかったもーん！これからもやろうでもっと！
It was so much fun! Let's do this even more!
やろう！やろう！じゃあ続いてフレア！
Let's do it! Next up is Flare!
あ、何も考えてなかった！そう！
Ah, I didn't think about anything either! That's right.
やっぱ私たちって、歌ってみたやりたくて集まったところもあって、でみんな歌が好きメンバーが集まっているからね、
After all, we gathered partly because we wanted to do cover songs, and since members who love singing are gathered here,
これからのいっぱい歌とかも歌いたいね！歌いたいね！歌いたいね！
we want to sing lots of songs together from now on! We want to sing!
すっごい今日楽しかったし、これからも一緒に歌っていこうね！
Today was so much fun, let's keep singing together from now on!
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
そらふぶちゃんかんしょして？
Sora-Fubuchan, check this out!
はい はい はい はい
Right, right, right, right!
ま、本日ね、バカタレ2周年ということで、なんと2年も連れ添っていた！
Well, today being Bakatare's 2nd anniversary, we've somehow been together for 2 whole years!
3Dライブやって本当にね、よかったよー！
Doing this 3D live really was great!
またね、来年3周年とかもライブとか何かしらできたらいいなと思っております！
And I hope we can do something like a 3rd-anniversary live next year too!
皆様、応援ありがとうございました！ありがとうございます！
Everyone, thank you so much for your support! Thank you!
はい、じゃあ最後の楽曲、じゃあちょっと、最後まででもね、やっぱり我...バカタレクライマックスしてこうよ！
Alright, then for the final song, well, let's go all the way to the climax as Bakatare!
そうだね、まだまだクライマックスまでね、もうちょっとありますね。
That's right, we still have a bit more until the climax, right?
ということで、次は、お？お？いいじゃん！いいじゃん！ジャンプして、ジャンプして、終わったら、ジャンプジャンプして終わりますか！
With that said, next is— oh? Oh? Jump, jump, when it's done, shall we jump and finish?
じゃあちょっと、せーの！せーの！
Now then, ready, set! Ready, set!
せーの、せーの、せーの、せーの、せーの、クライマックス好きね、クライマックス！
Ready, ready, ready, ready, ready, you guys love the climax, don't you? Climax!
時間の波を捕まえて
Let's catch the wave of time
今すぐ行こう約束の場所
And go to the promised place right now
限界無限 いざ飛び込め Climax Jump!
Know no limits, take the plunge, Climax Jump!
いーじゅん! いーじゅん! スゲージュン?!
Isn't it cool? Isn't it great? Isn't it awesome?!
叶えたい夢があるなら
When we've got dreams we want to realize,
信じなくちゃ 願った日々を
we must believe in the days we prayed for.
Catch the wave 迷いそうな時必ず
Catch the wave, whenever you feel lost,
思いの強さが導く
the strength of your feelings will guide you.
キミが望む未来すでにIn your hands
The future you desire is already in your hands.
始まりはいつも突然
Things always begin so suddenly,
運命を連れて行くTime tripin' ride
taking destiny along on this time tripin' ride.
不可能超えて 掴み取るさ Climax
Go beyond the impossible and seize your Climax.
変わることを恐れないで 明日の自分見失うだけ
Do not fear change, or you'll lose sight of tomorrow's self.
誰より高い空へ飛ぼうぜ Climax Jump!
Let's fly higher than anyone else into the sky, Climax Jump!
いーじゅん! いーじゅん! スゲージュン?!
Isn't it cool? Isn't it great? Isn't it awesome?!
胸の中 みんな密かに
Deep inside our chests, everyone secretly
書き換えたい記憶もある
has memories they wish they could rewrite.
Means nothing! 新しい朝を待つなら「今」を塗り替えろそこから
Means nothing! If you're waiting for a new dawn, repaint the 'present' right now.
ほんの少し勇気を持ってIn your mind
Hold just a little bit of courage in your mind.
旅立ちはいつも必然 どうせなら飛び回れTime tripin' ride
Journeys are always inevitable, so might as well fly around on this time tripin' ride.
捜し出すのさ自分だけのClimax
Search out your very own Climax.
昨日までの記憶すべて 必要と分かる日が来るハズ
The day will come when you realize all past memories were necessary.
誇れるように更なる Climax Jump!
So we can be proud, an even greater Climax Jump!
心を強くする 大切な言葉とか かけがえない思い出を集めて
Gathering precious words that make the heart strong and irreplaceable memories,
もう少しあと少し...届かない星空 諦めたらそこが終点さー
a little more, just a little more... the unreachable starlit sky, once you give up, that's the end of the line.
始まりはいつも突然 運命を連れて行くTime tripin' ride
Things always begin so suddenly, taking destiny along on this time tripin' ride.
不可能超えて 掴み取るさ Climax
Go beyond the impossible and seize your Climax.
変わることを恐れないで 明日の自分見失うだけ
Do not fear change, or you'll lose sight of tomorrow's self.
誰より高い 昨より高い Climax Jump!
Go higher than anyone else, higher than yesterday, Climax Jump!
いーじゅん! いーじゅん! スゲージュン?!
Isn't it cool? Isn't it great? Isn't it awesome?!
始まりはいつも突然 運命を連れて行くTime tripin' ride
Things always begin so suddenly, taking destiny along on this time tripin' ride.
不可能超えて 掴み取るさ Climax
Go beyond the impossible and seize your Climax.
変わることを恐れないで 明日の自分見失うだけ
Do not fear change, or you'll lose sight of tomorrow's self.
誰より高い 昨より高い Climax Jump!
Go higher than anyone else, higher than yesterday, Climax Jump!
いーじゅん! いーじゅん! スゲージュン?!
Isn't it cool? Isn't it great? Isn't it awesome?!
おわり
The End